JOHN WESLEY C

+91-8220383194 johnwesley.dev@gmail.com Chennai,TamilNadu

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A quality-focused Software Engineer around 4 years of experience in Telecommunication domain to develop applications in Mean stack(Angular2+,NodeJs) technologies that are capable of making calls, chat, emails, and chatbots integrated with Genesys cloud and AWS.

Extensive experience in Agile model and methodology with CMMI process for building solutions for customers' business demands and technical needs within timeline.

SKILLS

Angular ,TypeScript	AWS	C#
JavaScript,NodeJS	GitHub	MongoDB,SQL
HTML/Material/CSS	Docker	Rest Api,Expressjs

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Pointel Solutions Pvt Dec 2019 - Present

Agent Interaction Web

- Role: Developer, UI designer
- Duration: Dec 2019 Mar 2022(currently in support)
- Environment: Angular 8, ASP.net, SignalR, REST Api, Mongoose
- **Details**: The scope of the project is to manage various channels like voice, chat, and email by the agent in thin client. Which has the capability to integrate within 3rd party application such as Oracle service cloud Agent web browser, Salesforce and deploy in aws cloud.
- Team Size: 6
- Work Contributed: UI Design and Core logics in angular 8,Data management from MongoDb and Unit Testing.

Engage Cloud Softphone

- Role: Developer.
- Duration: Sep 2021 Mar 2022(currently upgrading).
- Environment: Angular 12, Nodejs, express js, socket js, REST api .
- **Details**: The scope of the project is to manage voice channel by the agent in thin client. Which has the capability to integrate within CRM applications such as Oracle service cloud Agent web browser and Salesforce.
- Team Size: 9
- Work Contributed: Made a SoftPhone UI in Angular 12 and Nodejs Core logics.

Dialog Builder

- Role: Developer, UI designer
- **Duration**: Dec 2022- Present
- Environment: Angular 14, ASP.net, SignalR, REST Api,C#
- **Details**: The scope of the project is to manage IVR calls in UI, Which has the capability tto make multiple ivr call at a time and check call feasibility.
- Team Size: 8
- Work Contributed: UI Design and Core logics in angular 14,Data management from ASP.net that makes user to create a ivr flow and Unit Testing.

Prudential IVR

- Role: Developer.
- **Duration**: Sep 2020 Mar 2022(currently upgrading).
- Environment: Genesys Cloud Architect.
- **Details**: The scope of the project is to make IVR inbound and transfer flows flows in Genesys Cloud and develop routing, scheduling api's to integrate with flows .
- Team Size: 6
- Work Contributed: R&D on Genesys Cloud architect and created multiple inbound and inQueue Flows.

EDUCATION

2021-2022 (7.5CGPA)

Madras University - MCA

2016-2019(6.5CGPA)

Madras Christian College - BCA

2014-2016(7.2CGPA)

Madras Christian High School